Contact

+16692584696 (Work) uday.kang@cicerotransact.co m

www.linkedin.com/in/uday-singh-kang (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Business Development
Management
Customer Service

Certifications

Best Management and Advisory Firm 2020

ENTREPRENEUR IN FOCUS 2019 ISO 9001:2015

Sales Enablement Certified Inbound Marketing Certified

Honors-Awards

20 MOST PROMISING CONSULTANTS OUTSOURCING CONSULTANTS - 2018

Entrepreneur In Focus 2019

Entrepreneur 40Under40 India (B2B Tech Startup Of The Year)

Uday Singh Kang

Solopreneur | Fractional CMO

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Summary

Entrepreneur India 40 Under 40 Nominee (2022) and marketing expert with a track record of building successful companies in AdTech, Marketing Automation, and Custom Marketing Solutions. Passionate about delivering outsized financial growth through datadriven marketing strategies.

A decade of experience in B2B and B2C marketing, lead generation, sales, and an advanced understanding of campaign processes. Known for building high-performing teams that excel on a foundation of operational rigor, financial discipline, and continuous optimization.

Committed to sharing insights and expertise on marketing automation, SaaS, and AI Implementation strategies. Connect with me to discuss how I can help elevate your marketing efforts and drive exponential growth for your business.

Experience

MarTechs
Founder | CEO
October 2020 - Present (2 years 9 months)
India

MarTechs OPC is a global provider of state-of-the-art marketing technology solutions for B2B businesses. Our proprietary technology platform combines smart strategies with marketing efforts to maximize prospect opportunities from existing website visitor traffic. We serve customers across numerous industries, including software, telecom, healthcare, technology, financial, professional services, manufacturing, and transportation. Discover the power of MarTechs and take your sales performance to new heights.

SynapTech Al Advisors Chief Advisor March 2023 - Present (4 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

At SynapTech Al Advisors, we provide a comprehensive suite of services designed to help businesses capitalize on the opportunities presented by artificial intelligence. Our expert team works closely with clients to develop and implement tailored Al solutions that drive growth, efficiency, and innovation across various industries.

Cicero Transact Business Platform 4 years 1 month Chief Marketing Officer January 2022 - Present (1 year 6 months)

Vice President Marketing
March 2021 - Present (2 years 4 months)
New York City Metropolitan Area

Director Of Sales Marketing
June 2019 - Present (4 years 1 month)
Briarcliff Manor, New York, United States

Cicero Transact is an exclusive online community dedicated to forging strategic business alliances. As a member, you have premier access to our user-friendly platform allowing an inside look at high-quality deal flow that includes startups, entrepreneurs and companies all seeking the necessary support required to enhance and execute their business models. We help companies with joint ventures, strategic partnerships, mergers and acquisitions, and the ability to do business internationally.

Our business platform offers a revolutionary new way to transact business with a global membership that covers every industry vertical.

Cicero Transact's business platform allows you to actively seek deals and opportunities that best suit your area of expertise. Members of Cicero Transact have the ability to review, participate in, and earn income on high-quality deal flow by leveraging their business contacts and connections.

Dyne Marketing Media Solutions Pvt. Ltd. Founder(Successful Exit 2018)
December 2017 - April 2019 (1 year 5 months)
Pune Area, India

HoneyKloud BPO Pvt Ltd

4 years 2 months

Head Of Operations : Australia B2B Appointment Setting May 2017 - October 2018 (1 year 6 months)

Pune Area, India

We have started with a new Australian B2B Appointment setting campaign in May.

The pilot run has been a great success.

Just a small introduction to our campaign.

We have a team of Business coaches worldwide who work with SMB's on 1-1 basis and help SMB's overcome any pain areas they have in their business with their hands on experience in their relevant work experience.

The first session is a one hour obligation free session for the business owners.

We are always looking for professionals who can help us grow and give their valuable feedback to us.

Business Development : Operations Manager B2B September 2014 - October 2018 (4 years 2 months) Kalyani Nagar , Pune

- Researching organisations and individuals online (especially on social media)
 to identify new leads and potential new markets
- Researching the needs of other companies and learning who makes decisions about purchasing
- Contacting potential clients via email or phone to establish rapport and set up meetings
- Planning and overseeing new marketing initiatives
- Attending conferences, meetings, and industry events
- Preparing PowerPoint presentations and sales displays
- Contacting clients to inform them about new developments with the companyis products
- Developing quotes and proposals
- Negotiating and re-negotiating by phone, email, and in person
 Developing sales goals for the team and ensuring they are met. Training personnel and helping team members develop their skills

Honeykloud LLC New Business Development August 2015 - July 2017 (2 years) Santa Clara, California Gautam Trading
Sales Manager
January 2014 - September 2014 (9 months)
Madagascar

Manage the sales administration function, operational performance reporting, streamlining processes and systems wherever possible, and advising senior management on maximizing business relationships and creating an environment where customer service can flourish.

Responsible for managing the sales team, developing a business plan covering sales, revenue, and expense controls, meeting agreed targets, and promoting the organization's presence throughout Africa

Responsible for obtaining profitable results through the sales team by developing the team through motivation, counselling, skills development and product knowledge development.

Salebuild Research Analyst September 2013 - January 2014 (5 months) Pune Area, India

- # Monitor and forecast marketing and sales trends
- # Measure the effectiveness of marketing programs and strategies
- # Devise and evaluate methods for collecting data, such as surveys, questionnaires, and opinion polls
- # Gather data about consumers, competitors, and market conditions
- # Analyze data using statistical software
- # Convert complex data and findings into understandable tables, graphs, and written reports
- # Prepare reports and present results to clients and management

Three.

CSR

September 2012 - September 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Pune Area, India

• Receive inbound retention calls from current customers, for sales and revenue generation, in a high-intensity call center environment.

- Utilize proactive persuasive/retention skills to turn requests for disconnection or downgrade into sales and save opportunities by identifying customer needs.
- Achieve monthly key performance metrics, call and order entry productivity standards, and call quality performance through utilization of persuasive skills, defined call flow structure, and adherence to provided schedule.
- Educate customers on active product features, service offerings, billing, charges, and product value.
- Understand and promote current marketing campaigns in order to sell to or save customers accurately and effectively.
- Increase revenue through up-selling and cross-selling video, HSI, wireless, and telephony services to existing customers.
- Research and review competitive pricing and service offerings in order to provide competitive price and product comparisons based on customer needs.
- Responsible for utilizing multiple customer databases to access, change or input account information for customers.
- Provide outstanding customer service, troubleshoot and resolve service and minor technical problems for customers by asking appropriate questions.
- Creatively negotiate pricing and bundling by making offers of credits and/or discounts according to Company guidelines.
- Complete installation, disconnect, transfer and seasonal downgrade orders and update customer accounts utilizing customer record database.
 Other duties as assigned.

EXL

CSE

June 2011 - September 2012 (1 year 4 months)

Pune Area, India

- Rated best performing customer support rep in a team of 20
- Answer calls in a prompt courteous manner.
- Manage customer service and administrative functions related to Insurance.
- Served as a basic point of contact for customers and intermediaries with complaints, queries, requests, feedbacks etc.
- Streamline workflow efficiencies and contact customers as well as intermediaries to investigate and resolve any disputes.
- Determine every possible reason behind each complaint of the client and make a decision with genuineness.

- Prepare reports that provide information in detail with regard to unresolved matters, personal customer information, action taken and relevant notes or comments, if any.
- Solve cross-functional customer issues related to issues like premium collections and fraud.
- Provide information to internal staff on communicating with clients, understanding issues, analyzing the options and solving problems with feasible solution.
- Manage calibration and training sessions for the new as well as tenured agents.
- Analyse outbound calls and provide guidance and constructive feedback to the agents on the basis of soft skills to achieve their performance goal.
- Prepare weekly and monthly reports based on the performance of the customer service executives.
- Communicate ideas and recommendations.

Education

Cusrow Wadia Pune University
Diploma, Mechanical Engineering · (2008)